Finding Aid for Graves family papers, 1833-1874
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Graves family papers 1833-1874
Graves family.
1 linear foot
85173 Aa 2
Grand Rapids, Michigan, family. Letters of Albert and Martha Calhoun Graves, including letters written during Civil War while Graves was a member of Co. B, First Michigan Engineers and Mechanics; also family letter reflecting daily life.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Miss Elizabeth D. Knapp (donor no. 6395 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Graves family were residents of Grand Rapids, Michigan. Albert Graves served with Co. B, First Michigan Engineers and Mechanics during the Civil War.
The Graves family collection consists of letters of Albert and Martha Graves written during his Civil War service. There are also other family letters, genealogical information, and various other financial and legal family documents.
Subjects:
Grand Rapids (Mich.).; Michigan--Social life and customs--1831-1840.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1841-1850.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1851-1860.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1861-1870.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; United States. Army. Michigan Engineers and Mechanics Regiment, 1st (1861-1865). Company B.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Women--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Military spouses--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.
Contributors:
Graves, Albert, 1825-1865.; Graves, Martha Calhoun, 1826-1904.
- Family papers
  - Graves family genealogy (Box 1)
  - Letters to parents and other family members, 1845-1854 (Box 1)
  - Courtship letters exchanged with Martha Calhoun (later Mrs. Albert Graves), 1847 (Box 1)
  - Civil War letters
    - 1861 (Box 1)
    - 1862 (Box 1)
    - 1863 (Box 1)
    - 1863 (from Martha to Albert) (Box 1)
  - Civil War miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Legal documents, probate court materials, marriage certificates (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous receipts. (Box 1)
  - Deeds, tax receipts, justice of the peace material (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, undated and fragmentary, etc. (Box 1)
  - Family letters of Graves and other family members
    - 1845-1850 (Box 1)
    - 1851-1855 (Box 1)
    - 1856-1862 (Box 1)
    - 1863-1865 (Box 1)
    - 1866-1874 and 1901 (Box 1)
  - Papers of Belle, Cora and Martha Graves, 1862-1905 and undated (Box 1)
  - Letters of Sheldon and Sally Calhoun, 1833 and 1836 (Box 1)